Keenan Brant

Software Developer

Barnsley (open to relocation)

07867-861-565 | keenan.brant@yahoo.co.uk | GitHub | Portfolio | LinkedIn

Profile

Junior software developer with full-stack skills and prior technical knowledge of computer hardware and software looking for a role where I can utilise my skills and expand upon them in a business production environment. I initially spent 2 years at Sheffield Hallam University studying Cyber Security and Computer Networks prior to Covid resulting in a career/education gap, in May 2023 I joined the Northcoders Software Dev Bootcamp where I developed coding skills and software practices with a focus on full-stack web development using JS frameworks and libraries and relational database management software skills that I have continued to develop going forward in my career path.

Technical Skills

 Software development technologies and practices displayed through projects displayed on <u>GitHub</u> Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript (Node.js), C# (.NET7), SQL

Testing: Test Driven Development (TDD), Jest, Swagger, Postman/Insomnia

 ${\tt Back-end: PostgreSQL, Node.JS\ w/\ Express,\ ASP.NET\ core,\ Entity\ Framework,\ migrations,}$

RESTful API

Front-end: HTML CSS, Tailwind CSS, React, React Native, VueJS, Ul/UX, responsive design

Hosting/Cl: Netlify, GitHub Actions, Docker Environments: Linux (Ubuntu), WSL, VS Code

Soft skills: Version control with Git, pair programming, technical communications, documentation, Software Development Lifecycle (SDL), Agile Scrum and Kanban, Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment (CI/CD)

 IT technical skills including maintaining and installing computer hardware directly, installation and maintenance of software and proficiency with software packages such as troubleshooting support software and the adobe CC suite.

Professional Experience

Trainee Software Developer, Northcoders Software Dev Bootcamp

May 2023 to Aug 2023

- Award winning 13-week software development bootcamp teaching Full-Stack and fundamental coding skills with a focus on PERN stack Web development and methodologies via project-based learning with portfolio pieces displayed on GitHub.
- Back-end skills demonstrated by a RESTful news API made with NodeJS, Express, PostgreSQL and Jest. This API was built and documented with CRUD routes and error handling using express middleware hosted with OnRender on-demand-windup service. Live Project I GitHub Repo
- Front-end skills demonstrated by a responsive mobile-first news web-app built using HTML, CSS
 and React. This app integrates with a RESTful API allowing users to post and modify data such as
 ratings and comments. <u>Live Project</u> | <u>GitHub Repo</u>
- Team development skills demonstrated by an independent team project using kanban and scrum methods with specifications involving outreach into new technologies using documentation to develop a cross-platform mobile app using React Native with Expo where I was primarily responsible for testing and developing geolocation and mapping functionality using Google Maps with Expo Location and displaying marked locations programmatically with data received from the backend team as well as having the task of designing native forms to enable other frontend team members to implement handling and auth functionality. FE Repo | BE Repo

Library Front Desk, Wath Public Library (Work Placement)

Dec 2017 to Dec 2017

- Working with the library database system to manage outbound and incoming inventory and reservations
- Providing customer service and IT technical support
- Management of incoming calls and payment to front desk or escalating to library manager

Product line worker, Vortex Clothing Co Ltd (Work Placement)

Dec 2015 to Dec 2015

- Operation of various graphics application machinery
- End of line quality assurance to meet the required standards
- · Preparation of graphics transferred from digital to physical format for machinery
- Stocking and maintenance of bespoke graphics equipment for regular customers and large orders
- Managing logistics and paperwork of orders due for distribution

Education & Qualifications

- Sheffield Hallam University Cyber Security and Computer Networks
 2018 2020
- Dearne Valley College, Manvers BTEC Level 3 Extended Diploma ICT (DMM)
- Netherwood ALC, Wombwell 6 GCSE's and 1 BTEC including English, Maths and
 Science at grades C

Projects

- IBDirect Electronic Medical Record software web-app created as an example of a solution to a
 problem affecting me and hundreds of thousands of Inflammatory Bowel Disease patients across
 the UK. Valuable input and feedback from an NHS GI Consultant was used in the development of
 this project, more detailed summary available in FE Repo link. Frontend created with a responsive
 mobile-device first approach using: React, TailwindCSS, TypeScript. Backend created with typesafe languages to match a HealthTech setting using: C#, ASP.NET MVC, Entity Framework,
 PSQL, Role-based JWT Auth, SignalR WebSockets. Live App | FE Repo | BE Repo
- AtomiFit WIP cross-platform fitness tracker mobile app planned to be accessible as a free app
 with planned features bridging the gap of those provided by current market offerings such as:
 detailed analytics, inclusion of time-tested programs, ML object detection for barbell path tracking.
 Planned one-time purchase freemium model for extended features without impacting the core
 objective of the app. Built with: React Native, Expo, TypeScript, DrizzleORM, Native SQLite. Repo
- **EIDewrito Voting JSON Builder** A maintained desktop app tool for ED Server hosts to quickly and easily create the required server files, includes mod support, local storage, accessibility and personalization features. Built with: React, TailwindCSS, TypeScript, ElectronJS. Repo

Hobbies / Interests

- Experimenting with new technologies and developing trends to exercise and develop problem solving skills in a dynamic and challenging environment while learning new software languages.
- Physical fitness involving technical knowledge, data tracking & analysis and personal growth.
- Maintenance of personal PC system including upgrading hardware as required.